Preliminary Guide to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Memorabilia Collection,, 1850-2000 MVC0029.MS
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mount Vernon Seminary and College Memorabilia collection
circa 1850-2000
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Cole, Timothy
Mount Vernon College
Mount Vernon Seminary
MVC0029.MS
16.75 Linear Feet
This collection contains memorabilia from the Mount Vernon Seminary and College campuses. The Mount Vernon Seminary began in 1875 as a private high school and junior college for women, founded by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999. Material in this collection dates between circa 1850 and 2000.
Arrangement
Organized into 5 series: Timothy Cole (1852-1941) Etchings, Suzanne J. Allan (nee Johnson) memorabilia, Textiles, Metals, and Chasseriau Etchings.
Historical note
The Mount Vernon Seminary began in 1875 as a private high school and junior college for women, founded by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999.
The first school of higher education available to women in Washington, D.C., Mount Vernon Seminary and College had five different locations throughout its history:
1875-1880: Elizabeth Somers began tutoring the young daughters of prominent Washington men in her home at 204 F Street, NW in Washington, DC.
1880-1917: The school moved to 1100 M Street, NW where it expanded rapidly to include three additional houses, a courtyard, tennis court, and basketball court.
1917-1942: Having outgrown its M Street location, the school moved to a 15-acre campus on Nebraska Avenue, NW. In 1942, the United States Navy took over the Nebraska Avenue campus to use its facilities for the war effort.
1943-1946: The school resumed courses in February 1943 at the top floor of a Garfinckel's department store building in the Spring Valley neighborhood of Washington, D.C.
1946-1999: Between 1944 and 1946, the school built a new 21-acre campus located on Foxhall Road in Washington, D.C. using money granted to the college by the United States Navy in compensation for the military takeover of its property.
The last Seminary class graduated in 1969, and the school was then officially renamed to Mount Vernon Junior College. In 1976, Mount Vernon College became an accredited four year college. In 1997, the Board of Trustees decided that the College would close as an independent institution. As of June 30, 1999, Mount Vernon became affiliated with The George Washington University.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains memorabilia from the Mount Vernon Seminary and College campuses including textiles, metal objects, etchings, and personal memorabilia. The material listed in this guide is processed and available for use, but there is additional material in the collection that is minimally processed and may not be available for research. Please contact Special Collections for more information.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Women's colleges; Women -- Education; Mount Vernon College; Allan, Suzanne J.; Mount Vernon Seminary; Hensley, Adelia Gates
- Timothy Cole (1852-1931) Etchings, 1888-1912 and undated; 1896-1899; Series 1; Cole, Timothy; 1.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains twenty signed wood-engravings by American artist Timothy Cole. The etchings were at one time displayed on the Nebraska Avenue campus of Mount Vernon Seminary and College. They date between 1896 and 1912, with the bulk dating between 1896 and 1899.
  Biographical / Historical
  Timothy Cole:(b London, 16 April 1852; d Poughkeepsie, NY, 17 May 1931). American wood-engraver of English birth. He was one of the most renowned reproductive wood-engravers of his generation. Cole was apprenticed in his early teens to a Chicago firm of commercial wood-engravers and spent several years in New York, working for such periodicals as Scientific American and the Illustrated Christian Weekly. In 1875 he began an association with Scribner's Illustrated Monthly Magazine (later the Century Magazine), which continued for the greater part of his career. The magazine was a leader in 'the golden age of American illustration', and its reputation derived in part from the excellence of its engravings, to which Cole made a decisive contribution. He was in the forefront of the 'new school' of wood-engraving, which sought to reproduce more faithfully the textures and tonal values of painting and opposed the prevailing doctrines of such conservative engravers as William James Linton, who was attempting to retain some artistic licence for the engraver. In recognition of Cole's extraordinary technical skill and his sensitivity to works of art, the Century Magazine commissioned from him a series of engravings after masterpieces owned by leading European museums. Cole spent 27 years on the project, returning to the USA in 1910 to undertake a similar commission in American museums. In addition to appearing regularly in the Century Magazine, Cole's engravings were published separately in portfolios and were used to illustrate such books as William James Stillman's Old Italian Masters (New York, 1892), J. C. Van Dyke's Old Dutch and Flemish Masters (New York, 1895) and Charles H. Caffin's Old Spanish Masters (New York, 1902). Source: Anne Cannon Palumbo. "Cole, Timothy." Grove Art Online. Oxford Art Online. 29 Apr. 2010.
  - Duchess of Devonshire and Child, 1897; Series 1; Image: 17.6 cm x 13.2 cm Block: 19.7 cm x 16.5 cm Sheet: 29.1 cm x 23.2 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Artist: Joshua Reynolds (1723-1792), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Duke of Devonshire, Chatsworth State: Signed wood-block 208 P.C. 304 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 2
  - Garrick and His Wife, 1896; Series 1; Image: 13.2 cm x 17 cm Block: 15 cm x 19.4 cm Sheet: 22.5 cm x 29 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 2)
    Artist: William Hogarth (1697-1764), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Windsor Castle State: Signed wood-block 203 P.C. 299 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 6
  - Mrs. Siddons, July 1896; Series 1; Image: 13.2 cm x 16.8 cm Block: 15.3 cm x 18.7 cm Sheet: 23 cm x 29 cm; Some adhesive staining and wrinkling along edges of sheet. (Flat box 1, Folder 3)
    Artist: Thomas Gainsborough (1727-1788), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: National Gallery, London State: Signed wood-block 211 P.C. 307 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 7
  - The Sisters, April 1899; Series 1; Image: 13.2 cm x 16.6 cm Block: 15.4 cm x 18.9 cm Sheet: 22.2 cm x 28.7 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 4)
    Artist: Sir Thomas Lawrence (1769-1830), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection:Charles Crews, Esq., London State: Signed wood-block 236 P.C. 332 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 9
  - Lady Derby, July 1898; Series 1; Image: 13.2 cm x 16.8 cm Block: 15.3 cm x 19.5 cm Sheet: 21.8 cm x 28.7 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 5)
    Artist: George Romney (1734-1802), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Charles Tennant, London State: Signed wood-block 217 P.C. 313 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 10
  - On the River Wye, September 1897; Series 1; Sheet still adhered to old matting along all edges.; Image: 17.8 cm x 13 cm Block: obscured by matting Sheet: 26 cm x 20.6 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 6)
    Artist: Richard Wilson (1714-1782), Welsh. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: National Gallery, London State: Signed wood-block 215 P.C. 311 S.
    Written on back: Mrs. A. W. Drake Number on removed 1937 frame: 13
  - Dante and Virgil Crossing the Stygian Lake, 1906; Series 1; Image: 17.5 cm x 12.8 cm Block: 19.2 cm x 14.8 cm Sheet: 29 cm x 22.5 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 7)
    Artist: Eugene Delacroix (1798-1863), French. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Louvre, Paris. State: Signed wood-block, 286 P.C. 386 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 15
  - Dido Building Carthage, August 1899; Series 1; Image: 20 cm x 13 cm Block: 21.9 cm x 15.2 cm Sheet: 28.7 cm x 22.9 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 8)
    Artist: J. M. W. Turner (1775-1851), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: National Gallery, London State: Signed wood-block, 238 P.C. 334 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 16
  - Ulysses Deriding Polyphemus, 1900; Series 1; Image: 20 cm x 13 cm Block: obscured by matting Sheet: 24.3 cm x 30.5 cm; Sheet still adhered to old matting along all edges. (Flat box 1, Folder 9)
    Artist: J. M. W. Turner (1775-1851), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: National Gallery, London State: Signed wood-block, 240 P.C. 336 S.
    Written on back: Mrs. A. W. Drake -- 31 W.10 Number on removed 1937 frame: 18
  - The Parson's Daughter, 1898; Series 1; Image: 13.3 cm x 13.7 cm Block: 15 cm x 15.7 cm Sheet: 22.6 cm x 27.9 cm; Staining in upper left corner of sheet. (Flat box 1, Folder 10)
    Artist: George Romney, (1734-1802), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: National Gallery, London State: Signed wood-block, 226 P.C. 312 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 19
  - Portrait of Lord Hathfield, March 1897; Series 1; Image: 13.2 cm x 16.9 cm Block: 15 cm x 19 cm Sheet: 24 cm x 30.5 cm; Adhesive residue and surface tears along top edge of sheet. (Flat box 1, Folder 11)
    Artist: Joshua Reynolds (1723-1792), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: National Gallery, London State: Signed wood-block, 209 P.C. 305 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 23
  - Shrimp Girl, 1896; Series 1; Image: 13.4 cm x 17 cm Block: obscured by matting Sheet: 20.4 cm x 26.1 cm; Sheet still adhered to old matting along all edges. (Flat box 1, Folder 12)
    Artist: William Hogarth (1697-1764), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: National Gallery, London State: Signed wood-block, 207 P.C. 298 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 27
  - The Sisters--Mrs. Sheridan and Mrs. Tickell, July 1897; Series 1; Image: 13.4 cm x 17.8 cm Block: 15.1 cm x 19.6 cm Sheet: 24 cm x 30.5 cm; Adhesive residue and staining along top edge of sheet from old matting. (Flat box 1, Folder 13)
    Artist: Thomas Gainsborough (1727-1788), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Dulwich Gallery State: Signed wood-block, 213 P.C. 309 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 28
  - Cicero's Villa, August 1897; Series 1; Image: 18 cm x 13 cm Block: 19.8 cm x 15.2 cm Sheet: 30.5 cm x 24.2 cm; Sheet still attached to old matt along top edge. (Flat box 1, Folder 14)
    Artist: Richard Wilson (1714-1782), Welsh. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Thomas Agnew and Sons, London State: Signed wood-block, 214 P.C. 310 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 31
  - Philip IV of Spain, 1912; Series 1; Image: 13 cm x 16.8 cm Block: 15 cm x 19.2 cm Sheet: 22.9 cm x 28.6 cm; Adhesive residue along top edge of sheet. (Flat box 1, Folder 15)
    Artist: Diego Velázquez (1599-1660), Spanish. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Frick Collection State: Signed wood-block, 317 P.C. 420 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 33
  - Head of Flora, 1890; Series 1; Image: 12.8 cm x 16.2 cm Block: 14.9 cm x 18.8 xm Sheet: 24.4 cm x 27.8 cm; Edges of sheet are torn and have adhesive staining and residue. (Flat box 1, Folder 16)
    Artist: Sandro Botticelli (1444-1510), Italian. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: From "Allegory of the Seasons" in Academy of Fine Arts, Florence. State: Signed wood-block, 132 P.C. 228 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 35
  - Princess Sophie--Daughter of George III, 1898; Series 1; Image: 13.2 cm x 19.3 cm Block: 14.8 cm x 21.2 cm Sheet: 22.4 cm x 28.8 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 17)
    Artist: John Hoppner (1758-1810), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Windsor Castle State: Signed wood-block, 220 P.C. 316 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 36
  - Fishing Boats off Yarmouth, 1899; Series 1; Image: 15.9 cm x 12.9 cm Block: 17.8 cm x 15.2 cm Sheet: 28.7 cm x 22.8 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 18)
    Artist: John Sell Cotman (1782-1842), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Collection of the late J. J. Colman, Esq., Norwich, England. State: Signed wood-block, 229 P.C. 325 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 38
  - The Halt, 1900; Series 1; Image: 16.4 cm x 13.2 cm Block: 18.3 cm x 15.1 cm Sheet: 28.8 cm x 22.6 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 19)
    Artist: George Morland (1763-1804), English. Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: The Louvre, Paris. State: Signed wood-block, 237 P.C. 333 S.
    Number on removed 1937 frame: 41
  - Othello Plate 8, Series 5; Image: 29.6 cm x 21.8 cm Block: 30.5 cm x 22.2 cm Sheet: 40.6 cm x 28.6 cm; Indentation in center of top border and left side of top border
  - Three Marys at the Tomb, 1888; Series 1; Adhesive residue around edges of sheet from matting.; Image: 18 cm x 13.2 cm Block: 19.6 cm x 15.6 cm Sheet: 24.8 cm x 19.5 cm (Flat box 1, Folder 20)
    Artist: Duccio (di Buoninsegna), (1278-1319) Engraver: Timothy Cole (1852-1931), American, born England. Collection: Opera del Duomo, Siena State: Signed wood-block, 102 P.C. 197 S.
- Suzanne J. Allan (nee Johnson) memorabilia, 1959-1961; Series 2; Allan, Suzanne J.
  Arrangement
  Arranged in original order.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Suzanne J. Allan, October 19, 2011 (2011.072)
  This series contains correspondence, graduation programs, event materials, napkins, and photographs. These materials were collected by Suzanne J. Allan (nee Johnson) during her time as a student at Mount Vernon College. The material is dated from 1959-1961.
  Women's colleges; Mount Vernon College; Mount Vernon Seminary
  - Memorabilia, 1959-1961; Series 2; 1 folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Textiles, circa 1879-2000; 1879-2000; Series 3
  This series contains various textiles from the Mount Vernon collection including: sports and academic uniforms, academic regalia, banners, and accessories.
  - Navy blue Mount Vernon Seminary Uniform from Nebraska Avenue, circa 1917-1942; Series 3 (Box 3)
  - White Mount Vernon Seminary Uniform from Nebraska Avenue, circa 1917-1942; Series 3 (Box 3)
  - Mount Vernon Seminary Athletic Association banner, circa 1940-1964; Series 3 (Box 4)
    The Mount Vernon Seminary Athletic Association banner that records the winning sports teams from 1941-1964. This banner is seen in a photograph from 1943 on page 131 of "Dear Daughters."
  - Mount Vernon Seminary athletic uniforms, circa 1940-1964; Series 3 (Box 4)
    Includes multiple uniforms from ca. 1940-1960. One cream, short-sleeved, button-up dress is labeled "Betsy Cann." There are also two mustard colored short-sleeved shirts labeled "Judy McAllister" and one mustard colored skort.
  - Five Mount Vernon Seminary middies, circa 1915-1930; Series 3 (Box 5)
    This box contains five middies, uniforms with sailor-inspired collars, worn at Mount Vernon Seminary. Middies were popular in the first quarter of the 20th century.
  - Five Mount Vernon Seminary middies, circa 1915-1930; Series 3 (Box 6)
  - Mount Vernon Seminary banner with rod, circa 1879-1969; Series 3 (Box 7)
    This gold rectangular banner has a with a wooden rod and the words "Mount Vernon Seminary" embroidered on it. It has gold fringe along the bottom.
  - Mount Vernon Seminary banner, circa 1879-1969; Series 3 (Box 8)
    This banner is very fragile and in poor condition. It is off-white with gold tassles and has the letters MVS on it in gold.
  - Mount Vernon Junior College blazers, circa 1950-1976; Series 3 (Box 9)
    Includes two white uniform blazers from Mount Vernon Junior College. One is embroidered with the name Mary C. Wayne. The other, embroidered with the name Suzanne Johnson, was donated by Suzanne Allan, class of 1961, and is pictured on the cover of the book, "Dear Daughters."
  - Mount Vernon Preparatory School blazer, circa 1950-1976; Series 3 (Box 9)
    Includes a red Mount Vernon Preparatory School Senior blazer.
  - Five Mount Vernon College green felt banners, circa 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 10)
    Banners are forest green with gold lettering that says, "Mount Vernon College Washington, DC."
  - Mount Vernon College light green felt banner, circa 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 10)
    Banner is light green with gold lettering that says "Mount Vernon College Washington, DC).
  - Mount Vernon College white felt banner, circa 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 10)
    Banner is white with gold lettering that says, "Mount Vernon College 1940-1990."
  - Mount Vernon College extra large blue, gold, and white banner, circa 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 11)
  - Mount Vernon College cloth pendant, circa 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 11)
  - Mount Vernon College 3X5 feet plastic banner, circa 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 11)
  - Mount Vernon College Washington, DC felt banner, circa 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 11)
  - Mount Vernon College large plastic banner with school shield, ca. 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 11)
  - Mount Vernon College red plastic banner with school shield, circa 1976-1998; Series 3 (Box 11)
  - Mount Vernon College silk scarf, circa 1960-1980; Series 3 (Box 12)
    Includes a white silk scarf decorated with images of the United States Capitol building and pink and yellow designs. "Mount Vernon College" is embroidered below each image. The scarf was made by designer Frankie Welch in Alexandria, Virginia. Welch's boutique in Aexandria was open during the 1960s and 1970s.
  - Two pairs wool gloves, circa 1915-1930; Series 3 (Box 12)
    Includes two pairs of wool gloves, possibly dating to ca. 1915-1930.
  - Wool cap, circa 1917-1942; Series 3 (Box 12)
    Includes a creme colored wool hat with the letter "W" embroidered on the front.
  - Mount Vernon College athletic uniforms and socks, circa 1970-1998; Series 3 (Box 13)
    This box contains athletic shirts, shorts, and socks from various Mount Vernon College sports teams including tennis, field hockey. Many of the uniforms are not labeled with the sport.
  - Mount Vernon College athletic uniforms, undated; Series 3 (Box 14)
    This box contains athletic shirts, shorts, and socks from various Mount Vernon College sports teams including tennis and field hockey. Many of the uniforms are not labeled with the sport.
  - The George Washington University at Mount Vernon groundbreaking t- shirts, 2000; Series 3 (Box 14)
    Includes two t-shirts commemorating George Washington University's groundbreaking ceremony at Mount Vernon on April 26, 2000.
  - Four commencement gowns, undated; Series 3 (Box 15)
  - Three commencement/academic regalia hoods, undated; Series 3 (Box 15)
  - Six commencement caps, undated; Series 3 (Box 15)
  - Two gold tassels for commencement caps, undated; Series 3 (Box 15)
  - Woven depiction of George and Martha Washington with two others, undated; Series 3 (Box 16)
    This box contains an image of George and Martha Washington and two other figures created by weaving thread through a perforated piece of thick paper.
- Metals, Series 4
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains metal objects (sterling silver, silver plated metals, brass, tin, etc.) from Mount Vernon Seminary and College. The objects include silverware, hollowware, trophies, commemorative plates, etc. and range in date from circa 1850 to 1987.
  Hensley, Adelia Gates
  - Tin child's plate, 19th century; Series 4 (Box 26, Item 2)
    Embossed with the ABC's around the edge. On plate, embossed with "WHO KILLED COCK ROBIN. I SAID THE SPARROW WITH MY BOW & ARROW. I KILLED COCK ROBIN" as well as an image of a robin with a bow in his claw and a dead robin with an arrow in its chest.
  - Pewter teapot, 1862; Series 4 (Box 26, Item 4)
    Manufactured by E.B. Mannind with a patent date of June 5, 1862
  - Silver plated candelabra, after 1865; Series 4 (Box 24, Item 5)
    Manufactured by Wilcox Silver Plate Co., founded in 1865 in Meridian, CT.
  - Sheffield plate repousse creamer, 1869; Series 4 (Box 24, Item 2)
    Stamped with U.S. Patent No 89784, which was registered in 1869. Made in Japan with Japanese patent number 59402. Also labeled with Negbaur N.Y. No 256.
  - Silver plated water pitcher, after 1883; Series 4 (Box 25, Item 1)
  - Silver plated teapot stand, circa 1886-1928; Series 4 (Box 22, Item 4)
    This piece accompanies a silver plated teapot made by E. G. Webster & Sons, a manufacturing company based in Brooklyn, NY with that name from 1886-1928.
  - Silver plated teapot, circa 1886-1928; Series 4 (Box 22, Item 5)
    This piece has many hallmarks on the bottom. The letters "E P N S" indicate that this piece is made of Electro-Plated Nickel Silver (often called German silver, a copper alloy with nickel and often zinc).
    The six stamps above the letters are the hallmark of E. G. Webster & Sons, a manufacturing company based in Brooklyn, NY with that name from 1886-1928.
    see: http://www.silvercollection.it/AMERICANSILVERPLATEMARKSTZQUATTRO.html
  - Sheffield plate serving tray on stand, 1887- circa 1958; Series 4 (Box 28, Item 7)
    The pinkish-orange color visible in various areas of the dish identifies it as Sheffield plate (layered combination of silver on top of copper). The combination of hallmark stamps (crossed keys, crown, and unidentifiable symbol-maybe a bell) identifies this as being made by Lawrence B. Smith Co. in Boston, MA. The company was in business from 1887 to circa 1958.
    see: http://www.silvercollection.it/AMERICANSILVERPLATEMARKSSDUE.html
  - Sheffield plate mesh dish on small stand, 1887- circa 1958; Series 4 (Box 27, Item 2)
  - 8 sterling silver bouillon spoons, 1888; Series 4 (Box 18, Item 1)
    The hallmarks on these spoons (lion, anchor, letter G) indicate that they were manufactured by Gorham Corporation Gorham Corporation, based in Providence, RI and founded circa 1815-1818.
    The pattern on these spoons is called Versailles and was pattented in 1888.
    see: http://www.replacements.com/webquote/GS_VER.htm (Round Bowl Soup Spoon (Bouillon))
  - Mixed metal trophy "Presented to the Future Senior Classes of M.V.S. by the class of 1907", circa 1907; Series 4 (Box 23, Item 3)
    Manufactured by Rostand Inc., established in 1890.
  - Sheffield plate tall vase, circa 1912-1922 (Object 2)
    This piece measures 9" wide at the base and 27 1/4" tall.
    A hallmark on the bottom indicates that this piece was manufactured by the Paul Revere Silver Co. and that it is Sheffield silver (silver plated on a copper base).
    The Paul Revere Silver Co. was based in Boston, MA and was in business from about 1912 to 1922.
  - Sheffield plate serving plate, after 1912; Series 4 (Box 28, Item 6)
    Manufactured by Paul Revere Silver Co (indicated by hallmarks), which was founded in Boston, MA in 1912.
  - 21 sterling silver teaspoons engraved with "1913-1914" (Box 18, Item 4)
    The lion and "W" in a circle on the handle indicate that these spoons were designed by the Whiting Manufacturing Company, formed in 1866 and bought by Gorham in 1924.
    The pattern of theses spoons is called
  - Sterling silver trophy plate on stand, circa 1915; Series 4 (Box 19, Item 5)
    Inscribed "To the Class of 1916 and all succeeding classes From the Class of 1915"